U.S. Steel Corporation Training Manuals 5342
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Steel Corporation Training Manuals
1940-1952
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Steel Corporation
5342
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Training manuals.
Manuals, workbooks, publications, and other training materials of the U.S. Steel Corporation.
5603913
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 08, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, January 20, 2016
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of manuals, workbooks, publications, and other training materials of the U.S. Steel Corporation.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
United States Steel Corporation.
5603913
- Handbook of Inspection Instructions for the P-47 Airplane (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Handbook of Inspection Instructions for the P-47 Airplane, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Commanding General, Army Air Force
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
- Instructor's Manual for Fundamentals of Powerhouse Supervision, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Instructor's Manual for Fundamentals of Powerhouse Supervision, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: New York State Civil Service Department Training Division
- Instructor's Manual: Stationary Engineering, I, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Instructor's Manual for Fundamentals of Stationary Engineering Part 1, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Instructor's Manual: Stationary Engineering, Part II, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Instructor's Manual For Fundamentals of Stationary Engineering Part II, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Boilermakers mathematics workbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Boilermaker Mathematics Workbook, Trade Apprentice Training, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Author: Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation
- Electricians manuals, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Electricians Trade Theory Manual, Elementary Controls I, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Electricians Trade Theory Manual, Elementary Controls II, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Electricians manuals, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Electricians Mathematics Work Book, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: Electricians Trade Theory Manual, Advanced Controls I, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Machinist mathematics workbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Machinist Mathematics Workbook, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Molder and coremaker trade theory workbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Molder and Coremaker, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: 2 copies
- Patternmaker mathematics workbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Patternmaker, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Physics workbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Physics Workbook, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Engineering lecture course, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: The Glenn L. Martin Engineering Lecture Course, 1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Author: G. W. Matlat, Glenn L. Martin
    Notes: Lectures 1 - 10
- Plane Tips, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Plane Tips, Engineering Educational Program, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Glenn L. Martin
- Pointers, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Pointers to Better Design and Production, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Glenn L. Martin Company
    Notes: No. D5 - D9
- Technograph, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Technograph, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: The Glenn L. Martin Company Engineering Education Program
    Notes: Number 1-5
- Engineering inspection, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Folder 1 of 2
  - Item 1: Engineering Inspection Training Course, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Notes: Memorandum of Conference
  - 1941, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Engineering inspection, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Folder 2 of 2
  - 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Oklahoma A & M College: School of Technical Training, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: School of Technical Training, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Author: Oklahoma A & M College
- Miscellany, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: "Industry-Wide Bargaining" Digest of Pamphlet, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Leo Wolman, Professor of Economics, Columbia University
  - Item 2: Engineering Procedure, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: The Glenn L. Martin Co.
    Notes: Engineering Lecture No. 14
  - Item 3: Lofting and Photographic Reproduction, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: Engineering Lecture No. 12
  - Item 4: Engine Mount Construction, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: Engineering Lecture No. 13
  - Item 5: Castings, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: Engineering Lecture Number 15
  - Item 6: What Price Change, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: Engineering Educational Program Lecture No. 16
  - Item 7: Exhaust Manifold Maintenance, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: American Locomotive Company & General Electric Company
  - Item 8: Maintenance and Adjustment Data, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 9: Schenectady, NY, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: Traction Motor Maintenance